Florante P. Singcak

London, W6 +447786409486 fpsingcak@gmail.com https://github.com/FlorSing

Highly competent with vast transferable skills gained from 15 years of career in data gathering, economic research, industry monitoring, investment analysis, financial analysis, financial modeling/forecasting, and technical analysis. Continuously upgrading skills while seeking the right opportunity to dedicate a full-time career for a well-established company.

Skills:

Web development: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Node.JS, Bootstrap, Web-API

Data: Excel, Python, Tableau

Graphics Design: Desktop publishing, Adobe Photoshop, Corel Draw, Photography **Admin:** Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher); Data entry (60 wpm)

Certifications:

Mar 2023 - Front-end Web Development (edX-Trilogy Skills Bootcamp)

Oct 2022 - Introduction to Tableau (Datacamp)

Feb 2022 - DevNet Associate (Skills Bootcamp - Open University & Cisco Networking Academy)

Jan 2021 - Cloud Computing Basics (Coursera)

Sep 2020 - Python Programmer Track Certificate (Datacamp)

Aug 2020 - Certified Associate in Python Programming (Python Institute, OpenEDG)

Work Experience:

Concierge/Porter/Caretaker (Dec. 2022 to present)

Claibon Property Services, Victoria, London

Provide temporary cover duties for various residential properties of company's clients in Central London.

Building Porter (Sept. 2021 to Dec. 2022)

Dorchester Estates, Marylebone, London

Deliver client reception services, front security and ad hoc maintenance duties for the headquarter building of a real estate company that provide serviced-offices and residential properties. Conduct patrols on all floors, common areas and fire exits. Greet and receive visitors to the building and answer all queries. Receive deliveries, parcels, and posts. Act upon tenant complaints and issues. Provide support for two other buildings owned and operated by the company. Monitor parking spaces and address any irregularities.

Self-employed (12 years, 2009 to 2021)

Online Trader, Private hedge fund, Philippine Stock Exchange

Self-employed (11 years, 2011 to 2021)

Housekeeping Services. Provide hotel-standard housekeeping/cleaning services. Entrusted with key-holding service. Dedicated service to various households in and around Kensington and Chelsea area.

Porter/Building Manager (4 years, 2007 to 2011)

Serviced Apartments, Mayfair, London

Managed the daily housekeeping and maintenance requirements of a block of residential flats in Marble Arch that are being short-let to tourists. Received and greeted visitors at the front desk. Provided friendly customer service assistance to all the guests. Maintained security and accurate record of keys. Supervised and arranged the schedule of housekeepers in relation to guests' bookings. Booked the services of engineers for maintenance requirements needing professional expertise.

Financial Analyst (5 years, 2002 to 2007)

Executive International Movers, Inc., Metro Manila, Philippines

Reported directly to the Managing Director. Carefully managed the overall finance and administration requirements of the company. Liaised directly with the Corporate Secretary and Legal Counsel on various issues needing legal requirements for the company. Outlined the yearly budget and target forecast for the company's operations. Submitted reports and recommendation to the Managing Director and the Board of Directors based on analysis and forecast of company's monthly financial results. Monitored and maintained all company bank accounts and transactions. Managed company's cash flow position while keeping an eye on costs and expenses. Managed account payables and receivables for all domestic and international accounts. Performed routine check of company's book of accounts and coordinates with the Chief Accountant on the monthly preparation of consolidated financial statements. Wrote various ad hoc reports to Managing Director as required.

Investment Analyst/Research Production Staff (4 years, 1997 to 2001)

Vickers Ballas Securities (Philippines), Inc.

Monitored the financial performance, trends, and operations of selected listed/public companies in the technology, transportation, construction, and cement industries. Developed and maintained financial model to forecast financial performance of selected companies using audited financial results/statements. Attended periodical stockholders' and investors' meetings to gather information and update on covered companies. Wrote company analysis and industry reports to be published for Sales Agents, Institutional investors, and private clients. Provided some technical analysis on stock price performance. Managed the layout, design, presentation, and distribution of all research reports and publications. Assisted the Research Director in editing reports and investment analysis of Initial Public Offerings. Maintained market database and statistics.

Investment Analyst (1 year, 1996 to 1997)

Philippine TA Securities, Inc.

Wrote investment recommendations and analyzed financial statements of all publicly listed food, beverage, and retail companies. Also provided some technical analysis and daily, weekly, and monthly market updates. Handled report presentation and layout.

Marketing Assistant/Research Analyst (4 years, 1992 to 1996)

Rizal Commercial Banking Corporation, Makati City, Philippines

Assisted the product officer in the implementation and monitoring of ongoing product developments such as deposit campaigns. Monitored ATM services. Provided middle management with analysis and forecast of relevant economic indicators, industry updates, and regional reports. Analyzed and prepared reports on the Bank's statistical performance and industry standing. Attended a six-month in-depth training on branch banking operations for officer level eligibility.

Research Assistant (1 year, 1991 to 1992)

University of Asia and the Pacific, Pasig City, Philippines

Wrote reports on construction and related industries (e.g., cement, iron and steel, and fabricated metal products). Assisted senior economists in preparing market environment analysis, project proposals, and economic briefings.

Education:

Masters in Business Administration (candidate, 2000) Bulacan State University, Philippines

Bachelor of Arts in Economics (1991) Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering (incomplete, 1988) Adamson University, Philippines

Volunteering:

Extraordinary Minister of the Eucharist (2007 to present), Our Lady of Mount Carmel & St. Simon Stock Parish, Kensington Church Street, W8.

Foundation Governor (2007), Saint Francis of Assisi Catholic Primary School, Notting Hill, W11